ljmu.ac.uk 2019-04-28

# Privacy and cookies | Liverpool John Moores University

## Privacy statement

Liverpool John Moores University deals with all personal information in a responsible manner that respects personal privacy.

The University is registered as a Data Controller with the office of the Information Commissioner as required under the Data Protection Act 1998. The University will only process personal data in accordance with the Data Protection Act and for the purposes notified to the Information Commissioner. The University policy can be found under About Us - Public Information.

#### Cookies

Cookies are small pieces of information that a website can store in your web browser to record and recall information about your visit. Our cookies store only information about your site usage and preferences, we do not store any **personal data** , such as your name or email address. 

#### How we use cookies

We use cookies in two ways:

To retain user preferences - for example, cookies stored by your web browser help us to recognise you if you return to our site at a later stage. This can save you time on future visits by storing information you may have previously entered onto our site or to make feature links relevant to areas of interest to you.

To collect website usage information – we track how visitors interact with the website, including where they came from, the pages they visited and the actions they took (e.g. clicked a button, completed a form). This is then used by us to provide a more personalised online experience and to optimise our website for our visitors. We do not track users once they leave the University website. 

#### Third party cookies

We sometimes embed photo and video content from websites such as YouTube. Webpages with this embedded content may set cookies from these websites. Similarly, when you use a share button a cookie may be set by the service you have chosen to share content through. LJMU does not control the transmission of these cookies and cannot block cookies from those websites. You should check the relevant third party website for more information on their privacy policy.

#### Managing cookies

If you wish to control what cookies you use, you can change your internet browser setting at any time. However, please note that in disabling cookies, your browsing experience may be adversely affected.

#### Student Recruitment Privacy Notice pertaining to data collection for communication  
Updated 23/05/2018

Liverpool John Moores University is providing you with this information in order for us to comply with the General Data Protection Regulations, which requires us to tell you what we do with your personal information. 

**Who is collecting the information?  **

Liverpool John Moores University as the “Data Controller”. 

**Who are we sharing your Personal Data with?  **

We will not disclose your data to third parties without your consent, except where they are acting as authorised agents for the University or where we are permitted or required to do so by GDPR. 

**Data we hold    
****Why are we collecting it/what we are doing with it (purposes)?  **

To record and respond to your enquiry or to register and administer your attendance at a Student Recruitment Event. Where you have given us consent to do so, we will use the details you have provided to contact you by post, email or telephone regarding: 

  * The promotion of our recruitment Open Days 
  * The promotion of other recruitment initiatives either, on-campus, on-line, on-location 

We collect your contact details, geographical information, information on your interests that relate to courses and events or recruitment activities on or off campus. 

**What is the legal basis for processing?  **

Where you have submitted an enquiry or registered for a Student Recruitment Event your personal data will be processed in terms of Article 6(1)(b) of the GDPR as it is necessary for the performance of a contract (i.e. our responsibility to provide you with the information requested or administer your attendance at an event you have registered for). 

Where you have given permission for us to contact you about further events or services your data will be processed under your consent as per Article 6(1)(a) of the GDPR. 

We will only email you about our events and services, or call TPS registered numbers, if we have your express consent to do so. We may send you post, unless you have asked us not to. 

You can withdraw your consent/opt-out of being contacted by the University for the purposes above at any time by sending an email to the Course Enquiries Team at [courses@ljmu.ac.uk](mailto:courses@ljmu.ac.uk). We will also provide opt-out options in all communications we send to you.

**How are we collecting this information?  **

We are collecting this information from the following sources: 

  * Web form on www.ljmu.ac.uk or an advert on social media
  * Direct emails to Student Recruitment email addresses 
  * Registrations for events 
  * Via tablets at events in an electronic format
  * From Applicants already in our SIS system, who have applied through UCAS, or directly to the University  

**Who can see this information?  **

Your information will only be accessed by Liverpool John Moores University Student Recruitment and Admissions staff, academics, authorised student ambassadors and service colleagues in other departments where an enquiry has been forwarded for a response. 

Your data may also be shared with the following services in order to communicate with you about events and activities that we think you might find of interest: 

  * Our Admissions service 
  * Our Academic departments 
  * Our Professional Services departments 

**How long is your information kept?  **

We will keep your information only for as long as we need it to provide you with information or services you have requested (notionally the academic year of interest + 5 years) to manage your relationship with us, to comply with the law, or to ensure we do not communicate with you after you have asked us not to. When we no longer need information, we will always dispose of it securely. (Anonymised statistics may be retained permanently). 

**How secure is your information?  **

For services provided locally by Information Services, information is stored on servers located in secure University datacentres. These datacentres are resilient and feature security access controls, environmental monitoring, backup power supplies and redundant hardware. Information on these servers is backed up regularly and use a wide array of technology to ensure data security is continually dealt with to high professional standards. The University has various data protection and information security policies and procedures to ensure that appropriate organisational and technical measures are in place to protect the privacy of your personal data. All Liverpool John Moores University staff who have access to your information have received data protection training. We only use third party systems to store and process your data for which we have completed a risk assessment exercise to ensure your data is secure. 

Please note we use the following secure 3rd party applications to process your data: 

**1\. iCapture (Data Collection Tool)  **

Please note that the University uses a secure third party data-capture application, iCapture, to manage the data you have provided. The application is only used for the purposes of capturing and backing-up your contact data and will not be used for any other purposes and your data will not be added to any mailing list or shared with any other third parties. We value your feedback and privacy – if you would like further information, please see [iCapture’s privacy policy](http://http//www.icapture.com/privacy/)

**2\. CRM Database  **

The University’s Enquiry Management System, MS Dynamics CRM, is commissioned by Liverpool John Moores University (Data Controller), in conjunction with Crimson Consultants and the Microsoft Corporation. The University takes its obligations with your data very seriously and will ensure that all appropriate safeguards and security provisions are in place and full compliance with its third party agreements and privacy notice are monitored. 

**Who keeps your information updated?  **

You have the right to update your own information at any time by: 

  * Unsubscribing via the link provided on the communications you received 
  * Notifying the Student Recruitment and Admissions Team of any changes to your personal data by writing to Student Recruitment and Admissions, Liverpool John Moores University, Tithebarn Street, Liverpool, L2 2QP or emailing [courses@ljmu.ac.uk](mailto:courses@ljmu.ac.uk)

**Will your information be used for any automated decision making?  **

No. 

**Is any other information available?  **

Access a copy of the University’s Data Protection policies

If you wish to complete a Subject Access Request to access the data we hold for you [contact foi@ljmu.ac.uk](mailto:contact%20foi@ljmu.ac.uk)

The [Information Commissioners Office](http://https//ico.org.uk/for-the-public/) provides a range of information for individuals and organisations.

#### Sound City Instagram applicant competition, March 2019  
Terms and Conditions

  * To be eligible to win tickets in this competition you must have firmly accepted an offer to study an undergraduate programme with LJMU starting in September 2019 or March 2020

  * Competition entries must include both the @ljmuphoto and #soundcityljmu tags. LJMU is not responsible for ensuring individual account settings allow entries to be viewed

  * The competition closes at midday on Friday 29 March

  * Winning entries will be chosen at random using random.org

  * Winners will be notified by Friday 5 April, initially via direct message or a comment tag on Instagram, with full information provided by email 

  * Five prizes are available, each comprising a pair of Sound City+ packages worth £165 (per pair, including transaction fee). Each package includes a three-day Festival Pass plus access to:   
The Sound City conference   
Secret artist sessions   
Sound City+ barbecues   
Drinks receptions and agent parties   
Sound City+ delegates' lounge   
Networking events

  * Tickets will be sent to the winner’s designated address ahead of the Festival, subject to LJMU verifying that winners meet the eligibility criteria (ie LJMU is their first choice university)

  * Winners will be responsible for their own travel and (if required) accommodation arrangements and costs

  * Tickets are not transferable and a cash alternative will not be offered

  * LJMU will add entries submitted via an Instagram Story to the @ljmuphoto Story and highlights

  * LJMU may re-use any entries – submitted by Instagram Story or feed post – in future marketing activity

  * LJMU reserves the right to not include any entries we deem unsuitable, including but not limited to indecent content or inappropriate language, at our discretion

  * Entrants into the competition shall be deemed to have accepted these terms and conditions

  * LJMU reserves the right to amend these terms and conditions

#### Sound City student competition, 3-10 April 2019  
Terms and Conditions

  * To participate you must be an LJMU student (with a live LJMU email address)

  * Three prizes are available, each consisting of a £50 bar tab for the festival

  * Prizes are not transferable and a cash alternative will not be offered

  * Bar tab confirmation will be sent to the winner’s designated email address ahead of the Festival

  * The competition closes at midday on Wednesday 10 April

  * Winning entries will be chosen at random, from all entries on the LJMU Facebook and Instagram competition posts, using random.org

  * Winners will be notified on the relevant social media platform with further details sent to their university email address

  * LJMU reserves the right to amend these terms and conditions

#### Sound City student bundle competition, 15-23 April 2019  
Terms and Conditions

  * To participate you must be an LJMU student (with a live LJMU email address) with a valid Sound City ticket

  * Two prizes are available, each consisting of a vinyl album bundle courtesy of Modern Sky Entertainment

  * Prizes are not transferable and a cash alternative will not be offered

  * Records will be sent by post to the winner's preferred postal address

  * The competition closes at midday on Tuesday 23 April

  * Winning entries will be chosen at random from all entries, using random.org

  * Winners will be notified on Facebook with further details sent to their university email address once they have responded and their details confirmed

  * LJMU reserves the right to amend these terms and conditions
